Elyas Arkin elyasarkint@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/elyasarkin/

+46707818446



## **Summary**

I am a developer with a very broad skillset. With experience working with HTML/CSS, JavaScript and ReactJS to create responsive and interactive applications and components of different sizes and scopes. During programs and projects I've learned and applied the most up to date ReactJS technologies like React Hooks, Custom API, NextJS and state management with Redux. I'm proficient with the MERN-stack and have worked on a wide array of projects and assignments.

In the backend of things I have a fundamental understanding of NodeJS, ExpressJS and related technologies. I've extensive experience of working with and applying agile working methodologies, both as a web developer and as a tester.

As a tester I have experience working with test automation using Selenium and a solid understanding of Java. With a firm understanding of the entire process of developing web applications and he has hands-on experience from every aspect of the development process.

#### **About Elyas**

## Roles

- Web development
- Unit Testing / Test Automation



#### **Past Experiences**

#### **Codify College**

Web Developer

Studied and worked with Full Stack web development within the MERN-stack, specializing in Frontend development using ReactJS and related frameworks and technologies such as Babel, Webpack, NextJS, Redux, etc. Developed several projects implementing agile methodologies and relevant design patterns in different cases and groups.

#### Cybertech

**Test Automation Engineer** 

Developed, documented and implemented best practices for test automation in Java using tools such as: Selenium WebDriver, Cucumber, JUnit, Maven and Jenkins.

# Technologies, tools and environments

# Methods/models

- Scrum
- Model View Controller (MVC)
- OOP
- Module Design Pattern
- CI/CD



## Languages

- JavaScript
- Java
- HTML/CSS
- SQL

# Frameworks/Technologies

- ReactJS
- Context API
- NextJS
- React Router
- React Hooks
- Redux
- Babel
- Webpack
- Axios
- NodeJS
- MongoDB
- Mongoose
- ExpressJS
- Linux
- NPM
- Maven
- Selenium WebDriver
- Git
- Jenkins

#### **IDEs**

- VS Code(JavaScript/Java)
- Eclipse (Java)
- IntelliJ(Javascript/Java)

## **Past Experiences**

## Codify College (2020/09 – ongoing)

An intensive Web Development bootcamp delving into the MERN- stack and taking part in projects, presentations and cases using all the relevant technologies in the MERN-stack. During 15 weeks, participated in projects, in both groups and solo, where different agile methodologies were to be applied. Developing a wide array of projects, everything from responsive web pages for different IT-consultancies and Sports News websites using JavaScript and HTML/CSS to a Bookstore application using NodeJS, ExpressJS and MongoDB. However the main focus being React development and related technologies such as: Babel, Webpack, Redux, and Axios just to mention a few. Regularly worked with different cases using relevant technologies and working with mock-presentations, emulating real-life situations.

- JavaScript
- HTML/CSS
- NodeJS
- ExpressJS
- MongoDB
- Git
- Linux
- VS Code
- NPM
- Heroku

- ReactJS
- Context API
- NextJS
- React Router
- React Hooks
- Redux
- Babel
- Webpack
- Axios



# **Cybertech (2019/03 – 2020/05)**

A training program where I learned both fundamental and advanced techniques of Unit Testing and Test Automation. Was a part of two large scale projects as a tester where I participated in teams with both frontend and backend developers. The first one being Uplift application, a CRM application, and second one being Fleetapps, a car rental app, working with both manual tests and test automation using Selenium WebDriver, JUnit and tools like Maven and Cucumber.

- Selenium WebDriver
- Java
- JUnit
- Jenkins

- Maven
- Cucumber
- Eclipse

## Education, courses and certificates

2019-2020 Cybertech - Test Automation Engineer

2020- ongoing Codify College - Fullstack Web Development Bootcamp - 15 Weeks